All right, hopefully you've survived
thus far and if you hang in there a
little longer, we're about to cover my
favorite subject. Um, this time we are
covering arrays. Why are arrays my
favorite? Because by the time we've hit
this point, if you can use arrays
effectively, you can build anything that
you want. Arrays in combination with
loops and selection and math, string
manipulation, with that you can build
just about anything you want. There are
things that we will learn in the future
that will make your life easier. But the
things we've learned thus far, you can
build anything you want after you learn
arrays. Um, so I'm excited to give that
knowledge to you. Hopefully it's
helpful. So what is an array? Um, well,
an array is just a variable. So if we
think back to other variables, I
described them as a box. And a box could
hold something. So I showed you a box
that was holding like action figures.
Um, and I showed you another box. And I
told you to name your variables
descriptively.
Well, today I'm here to tell you that
one special type of box is called an
array. The reason it's a special type of
box is because it can actually hold
multiple pieces of information. So all
of the previous variables, an integer,
when we put an integer in something,
that type of box could only hold one
value. It could only be 18 or 22.5 if it
was a float or the string hello. Well,
arrays are really cool because they
allow you to hold multiple things in one
box. So, to visualize this, I bought a
little divider to show you.
Okay, hopefully you can see this. So,
this is like an array. Um, as you can
see, it is one box and I could move it
around
and everything inside of it moves with
the box. Here on the box, I've actually
got it labeled. So I've got a position 1
2 3 4 5 and six. And I realized after I
made this box that I should have started
at zero because computers start at zero.
But oh well, you live and you learn. So
um this represents an array. So when I
said an array is like a box, the entire
thing here is like one big container.
Inside of that box, it's subdivided into
six smaller boxes. Your array is
subdivided into six smaller storage
containers. So if I said go to my big
divider box and grab the thing in box
one, you would come to this divider box.
You'd open up the box and you'd find a
charging cable.
If I said grab what's in box two, you
would open it up and you'd find a
different charging cable. If I said grab
what's in box three, you'd open it up
and find a pair. So the point of an
array is that it is one big container
that you can move around, but it also
has smaller containers within it that
are holding information. So just like um
my multiple dividers in my container,
your arrays can contain multiple things
as well. So they can store a couple of
numbers and a couple of pieces of text
and a bunch of other things. Anything
you want to store, the great thing about
an array is that you can store it. The
other nice thing about arrays, unlike my
little box divider here that I just
showed you, is that they can expand and
they can contract based on how much
information you decide to put in them.
And so that is where we're going and
I'll show you how to implement that in
code. Thanks for watching.